Yassine Benchekroun

Yassine.b3n77@gmail.com | +212 681112753 Massira 1 A, No 567, Morocco

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Yassine is a senior back-end web developer with over five years of experience in Python, Django, and OpenCV, including image and video processing. A specialist in building back-end APIs for web applications, he thoroughly understands the requirements for solid builds. Yassine strives to provide the best infrastructures to facilitate growth and scaling safely and quickly. He is passionate about turning his ideas into projects, especially when they empower others to improve their quality of life.

SKILLS

- Django
- Python
- React.js
- Data Scraping
- Web Scraping
- Full-Stack Development
- REST APIs
- Django REST Framework
- OpenCV

- Machine Learning
- Artificial Intelligence(AI)
- C
- Linux
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- GIT

WORK HISTORY

Django Full-Stack Developer | SiteMatrix

02/2022 - 05/2024

- Developed a web app to buy and sell domains from all major domain providers. The admin user can control all transactions from the panel based on rich chart graphs, and customer users can register as solo traders or as a company to trade domains.
- Tracked and fixed bugs using Trello as the project management platform.
- Implemented the back end in Django 3.0 using Celery and RabbitMQ as the automation task system. The front end was implemented using the latest version of React.

Full-Stack Developer | Sliding Door Wardrobes

02/2020 - 01/2022

- Developed a dynamic website for the company to present its product to clients and sell wardrobes.
- Created the web design and implemented it using React and Next.js.
- Built the back end for book appointments, brochure downloads by filling in client data, and a contact form using third-party packages.

Full-Stack Developer | Site Matrix, LLC

09/2018 - 01/2020

- Developed REST API web huge app using Django. Implemented user auth services using JWT and Postgres as a database.
- Delivered microservices to retrieve domain data from domain management systems and trade domains based on that information.
- Developed the front end from scratch using React.
- Delivered async task management in Django using Celery and RabbitMQ.
- Added new features into a web app in the front and back end using Django and React.
- Tested apps using pytest and performed manual tests on the apps' front-end.
- Created a task management system to look at task running results from the admin panel.

EDUCATION

University of Al-Qadisiyah 05/2018

Bachelor's degree: Computer engineering

Mohammed V high school 05/2014

Diploma(3 years): Computer Science

LANGUAGE

• English : Fluent

• Arabic : Native or Bilingual